# Colin Welshofer

Software Developer

(615) 785-9014

Cwelshofer@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ colin-welshofer-6389a61b2/ https://github.com/Cwelshofe r

#### **About Me**

I have always worked hard to try and find a career that truly fits me. I had not heard of coding until one of my family friends recommended it to me because I had been talking to them about it. So I went to attend a 3 week jumpstart, and since then I have discovered my love of coding because I feel like it is truly a challenge, and I feel like I am truly suited to the job which I had not felt previously. I also identify with the people that work in coding a lot as well. It is now my dream to make a career of it.

### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School, Software Developer

A six month bootcamp that teaches full stack development through remote learning environment.

- HTML, Javascript, CSS, React and JSON are covered in the course
- Daily team stand ups in a virtual environment
- Learning to set up data structures for projects online
- Implemented full CRUD functionality for those projects

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Avian Glen Winery**, Smyrna TN — Assistant Manager

January 2018 - December 2019

- Individually responsible for sales, inventory, and general upkeep most of the week
- Assisted in planning for events and scheduled them for them.
- Helped/ ran events for different groups of people for wedding receptions etc
- Scheduled deliveries for the winery
- Maintained general cleanliness through the week

# **Geodis,** Mount Juliet, TN — Warehouse Worker

August 2017 - December 2018

- Worked on a team to package and label iphones to be sent out for shipping
- Worked in a warehouse taking inventory and making sure numbers are right
- Worked in a team environment and helped out in other departments, such as unloading shipping trucks

# **Technologies**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Python, Github

# **Projects**

Kustom Kidney Cookbook — Kustom Kidney Cookbook is a Application developed using React, Javascript and CSS. It is an application primarily aimed towards people who have medical issues with their kidneys and are on the renal diet. This application allows users to add recipes to a custom database. The app has full CRUD functionality, and uses a JSON server to store the recipes in the database.

https://github.com/Cwelshofe r/kustomkidneycookbook

Nutshell -- It is a project that allows you to make tasks, news, events. My role in the project was to have the ability to create tasks, and general styling of the webpage. It was developed using Javascript and CSS, and has full CRUD functionality using JSON server as well as login authentication.

https://github.com/NSS-Day -Cohort-42/nutshell-lizardcollectors

# **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School, Location — Software Development Bootcamp -Certificate

# Ingram — La Vergne, TN -- Book Stocker

January 2017 - August 2017

- Stocked books in a large warehouse
- Helped maintain cleanliness
- Organized the warehouse together